{
    "Exam Name": "CC Practice Exam",
    "Number of Questions": 50,
    "Default Time": 120,
    "Instructions": "These are custom instructions for this specific exam bank.  Read them carefully!",
    "DomainPercentages": {
        "ISC2 CC Domain 1: Security Principles": 20,
        "ISC2 CC Domain 2: Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response Concepts": 20,
        "ISC2 CC Domain 3: Access Controls Concepts": 20,
        "ISC2 CC Domain 4: Network Security": 20,
        "ISC2 CC Domain 5: Security Operations": 20
    },
    "Questions": [
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 1: Security Principles",
            "Question": "A company is concerned about unauthorized physical access to its data center. Which of the following controls would be the MOST effective in preventing this?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Implementing a strong password policy.",
                "B. Installing mantraps with biometric authentication",
                "C. Conducting background checks on employees.",
                "D. Using security awareness training."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "B. Installing mantraps with biometric authentication",
            "Explaination": "Explanation: Mantraps, which are rooms with two doors requiring separate authentication methods, are specifically designed to prevent unauthorized physical access. While the other options contribute to security, they do not directly address physical breaches."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 1: Security Principles",
            "Question": "An organization identifies that its executives are being targeted with sophisticated phishing emails attempting to obtain sensitive information. What type of social engineering attack is this an example of?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Phishing.",
                "B. Whaling",
                "C. Pretexting.",
                "D. Baiting."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "B. Whaling",
            "Explaination": "\nExplanation: Whaling attacks are phishing attacks specifically targeting high-ranking members of an organization. While it is a type of phishing, the focus on high-level executives makes \"whaling\" the most accurate answer."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 1: Security Principles",
            "Question": "During a risk assessment, a security analyst determines that a critical server has a vulnerability. The likelihood of exploitation is high, and the impact would be severe. According to basic risk management principles, what should be the FIRST course of action?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Accept the risk.",
                "B. Transfer the risk.",
                "C. Mitigate the risk",
                "D. Avoid the risk."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. Mitigate the risk",
            "Explaination": "Explanation: Risk mitigation involves implementing controls to reduce or eliminate risks. Given the high likelihood and severe impact, mitigation should be prioritized."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 1: Security Principles",
            "Question": "An organization wants to ensure that employees understand their responsibilities regarding data security. Which of the following is the BEST way to achieve this?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Implementing a firewall.",
                "B. Conducting regular security awareness training.",
                "C. Enforcing a strong password policy.",
                "D. Performing vulnerability scans."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "B. Conducting regular security awareness training.",
            "Explaination": "Explanation: Security awareness training educates employees about security threats and their roles in preventing them. While the other options are important security measures, they don't directly ensure employee understanding and responsibility."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 1: Security Principles",
            "Question": "Which of the following is the PRIMARY goal of implementing the principle of least privilege?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. To ensure data confidentiality.",
                "B. To prevent denial-of-service attacks.",
                "C. To limit the potential damage from insider threats",
                "D. To comply with legal regulations."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. To limit the potential damage from insider threats",
            "Explaination": "Explanation: The principle of least privilege minimizes potential damage by ensuring users only have necessary privileges. While it supports confidentiality, its primary aim is to limit the scope of potential misuse or compromise."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 1: Security Principles",
            "Question": "An organization needs to implement a system that ensures a user cannot deny having sent an email. Which security concept is MOST relevant?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Authentication.",
                "B. Authorization.",
                "C. Non-repudiation",
                "D. Confidentiality."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. Non-repudiation",
            "Explaination": "Explanation: Non-repudiation ensures that a user cannot deny taking an action. Digital signatures, logs, or timestamps are used to prove an action was taken by a specific user."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 1: Security Principles",
            "Question": "A company's security policy states that all employees must use strong passwords. Which document would provide detailed, step-by-step instructions on how to create and manage these passwords?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Security Policy.",
                "B. Password Standard",
                "C. Password Guideline.",
                "D. Acceptable Use Policy."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "B. Password Standard",
            "Explaination": "Explanation: Standards translate policies into actionable rules, such as password requirements. Policies are high-level statements, while procedures offer detailed instructions."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 1: Security Principles",
            "Question": "A security manager is reviewing physical security controls for a data center. Which of the following controls is considered a detective control?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. A fence.",
                "B. A locked door.",
                "C. A CCTV system",
                "D. A turnstile."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. A CCTV system",
            "Explaination": "Explanation: CCTV (closed-circuit television) systems monitor the facility and detect potential intruders. Fences, locked doors, and turnstiles are preventative controls."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 1: Security Principles",
            "Question": "An organization is determining how much risk it is willing to accept to achieve its business goals. Which risk management concept does this BEST describe?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Risk capacity.",
                "B. Risk tolerance",
                "C. Risk appetite",
                "D. Residual risk."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. Risk appetite",
            "Explaination": "Explanation: Risk appetite is the amount of risk an organization is willing to accept. Risk tolerance is the acceptable deviation from that appetite"
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 1: Security Principles",
            "Question": "A cybersecurity analyst discovers that a user's account has been compromised. The account had access to sensitive financial data, but the analyst is unsure if the attacker accessed the data. Which security principle is MOST at risk?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Availability.",
                "B. Integrity.",
                "C. Confidentiality",
                "D. Non-repudiation."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. Confidentiality",
            "Explaination": "Explanation: Confidentiality is most directly at risk when unauthorized access to sensitive data occurs. Even without confirmation of access, the potential exposure violates confidentiality."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 2: Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response Concepts",
            "Question": "An organization experiences a server failure that disrupts critical business operations. Which plan should be initiated FIRST to ensure essential functions continue?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Business Continuity Plan (BCP).",
                "B. Disaster Recovery Plan (DRP).",
                "C. Incident Response Plan (IRP).",
                "D. Communication Plan."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "A. Business Continuity Plan (BCP).",
            "Explaination": "The Business Continuity Plan (BCP) focuses on maintaining essential business functions during disruptions. The Disaster Recovery Plan (DRP) focuses on restoring systems after a disruption."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 2: Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response Concepts",
            "Question": "During a disaster recovery, the IT team is working to restore systems to the last known reliable state of operation. Which of the following is the PRIMARY objective of this effort?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Maintaining crucial company operations.",
                "B. Ensuring a safe escape procedure.",
                "C. Communicating the damage to stakeholders.",
                "D. Restoring company operation to the last-known reliable state."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "D. Restoring company operation to the last-known reliable state.",
            "Explaination": "The primary goal of a Disaster Recovery Plan (DRP) is to restore the business to the last-known reliable state of operations."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 2: Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response Concepts",
            "Question": "An organization wants to minimize data loss during a disaster. Which of the following metrics is MOST relevant to determining the frequency of data backups?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Recovery Time Objective (RTO).",
                "B. Maximum Tolerable Downtime (MTD).",
                "C. Recovery Point Objective (RPO).",
                "D. Mean Time to Repair (MTTR)."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. Recovery Point Objective (RPO).",
            "Explaination": "Recovery Point Objective (RPO) identifies the maximum acceptable data loss. It helps determine how far back the data can be recovered, thus influencing backup frequency."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 2: Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response Concepts",
            "Question": "An employee discovers a suspicious email and reports it to the security team. Which phase of the incident response process does this represent?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Containment.",
                "B. Eradication.",
                "C. Detection and Analysis.",
                "D. Recovery."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. Detection and Analysis.",
            "Explaination": "Incident Response involves detecting events to mitigate risk. The process includes identifying and responding to security incidents to minimize damage."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 2: Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response Concepts",
            "Question": "Which of the following roles is PRIMARILY responsible for overseeing the application of the ISC2 Code of Ethics within an organization?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Incident Response Manager.",
                "B. Chief Information Officer (CIO).",
                "C. Professional Conduct (Ethics) Committee.",
                "D. Security Analysts."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. Professional Conduct (Ethics) Committee.",
            "Explaination": "The Professional Conduct (Ethics) Committee is established to oversee the application of the ISC2 Code of Ethics."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 2: Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response Concepts",
            "Question": "An organization wants to ensure that its incident response team (IRT) has the necessary skills and expertise. Which of the following models would be BEST to achieve this?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Pre-existing.",
                "B. Dedicated.",
                "C. Hybrid.",
                "D. Leveraged."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. Hybrid.",
            "Explaination": "Incident response teams can be Leveraged, Dedicated, or Hybrid."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 2: Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response Concepts",
            "Question": "What is the FIRST step in building a Business Continuity Plan (BCP) or Disaster Recovery Plan (DRP)?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Implement, Training, and Testing.",
                "B. Recovery Strategy Plan and Design.",
                "C. Project initiation.",
                "D. Identify Preventive Controls."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. Project initiation.",
            "Explaination": "The steps to build a BCP/DRP include Project initiation, Scope the Project, BIA, Identify Preventive Controls, Recovery Strategy Plan & Design, Implement, Training, Testing, and Maintenance."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 2: Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response Concepts",
            "Question": "During incident response, which action helps in minimizing the impact and preventing further damage?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Identifying the incident.",
                "B. Analyzing the root cause.",
                "C. Containment.",
                "D. Recovery."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. Containment.",
            "Explaination": "Key objectives of Incident Response are to detect and respond to incidents and contain and mitigate impact."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 2: Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response Concepts",
            "Question": "An organization is developing a disaster recovery plan. Which of the following is an essential element to include in the plan?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. A list of all IT assets.",
                "B. A marketing strategy for post-disaster communication.",
                "C. Checklists for recovery procedures.",
                "D. A detailed budget for recovery efforts."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. Checklists for recovery procedures.",
            "Explaination": "A DRP checklist ensures that the process is followed."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 2: Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) & Incident Response Concepts",
            "Question": "What should an organization prioritize during the immediate aftermath of a disaster?",
            "Choices": [
                "A. Data restoration.",
                "B. IT infrastructure recovery.",
                "C. People's safety.",
                "D. Business process optimization."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "C. People's safety.",
            "Explaination": "In disaster impact recovery, people's safety is the first priority."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 3: Access Controls Concepts",
            "Question": "A security administrator is implementing access controls for a data center. Which of the following is the MOST effective <b>physical control</b> to prevent unauthorized entry?",
            "Choices": [
                "Security awareness training",
                "Biometric authentication",
                "Security policy",
                "Turnstiles"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Turnstiles",
            "Explaination": "Turnstiles are physical access control mechanisms that prevent unauthorized entry by allowing only one person to pass at a time, offering a tangible barrier."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 3: Access Controls Concepts",
            "Question": "An employee is terminated but still has access to sensitive company data. Which of the following logical access controls should be implemented IMMEDIATELY?",
            "Choices": [
                "Implement a new firewall rule",
                "Conduct security awareness training",
                "Revoke the employee's access privileges",
                "Change the default passwords on all systems"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Revoke the employee's access privileges",
            "Explaination": "Revoking access privileges ensures the terminated employee can no longer access sensitive data, directly addressing the immediate risk."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 3: Access Controls Concepts",
            "Question": "Which of the following access control models gives the data owner the MOST discretion in granting access to resources?",
            "Choices": [
                "Mandatory Access Control (MAC)",
                "Role-Based Access Control (RBAC)",
                "Discretionary Access Control (DAC)",
                "Rule-Based Access Control"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Discretionary Access Control (DAC)",
            "Explaination": "Discretionary Access Control (DAC) allows owners of files, computers, and other resources to configure permissions as they see fit."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 3: Access Controls Concepts",
            "Question": "An organization wants to implement a security measure to ensure that no single person can perform critical tasks alone. Which of the following principles should be applied?",
            "Choices": [
                "Least privilege",
                "Need-to-know",
                "Segregation of duties",
                "Job rotation"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Segregation of duties",
            "Explaination": "Segregation of duties divides tasks among multiple persons to prevent fraud or errors by ensuring no single person has control over all aspects of a critical process."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 3: Access Controls Concepts",
            "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes the purpose of <b>two-person integrity</b>?",
            "Choices": [
                "To ensure two people are required to perform a sensitive process",
                "To enforce separation of duties",
                "To require two people to be present for any access to a sensitive area",
                "To provide redundancy in case one person is unavailable"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "To require two people to be present for any access to a sensitive area",
            "Explaination": "Two-person integrity requires that two people be present for any access to a sensitive area, such as where valuable items are stored. Two-person control, by contrast, is used to control access to very sensitive functions, requiring the concurrence of two individuals to carry out an action."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 3: Access Controls Concepts",
            "Question": "What is the PRIMARY goal of <b>least privilege</b>?",
            "Choices": [
                "To ensure all users have access to necessary resources",
                "To simplify access control administration",
                "To minimize potential damage from security breaches",
                "To comply with regulatory requirements"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "To minimize potential damage from security breaches",
            "Explaination": "The principle of least privilege says that users should have only the minimum set of privileges necessary to carry out their job responsibilities."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 3: Access Controls Concepts",
            "Question": "Which of the following is an example of <b>multi-factor authentication (MFA)</b>?",
            "Choices": [
                "Using a complex password",
                "Using a fingerprint scanner",
                "Using a smart card",
                "Using a password and a one-time password (OTP) from a mobile app"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Using a password and a one-time password (OTP) from a mobile app",
            "Explaination": "Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) combines two or more authentication methods for stronger security. A password is something you know, and a one-time password is something you have."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 3: Access Controls Concepts",
            "Question": "Which of the following is the MOST important reason to implement <b>security controls</b> in a physical environment?",
            "Choices": [
                "To comply with industry regulations",
                "To reduce insurance premiums",
                "To limit access to sensitive facilities",
                "To improve employee morale"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "To limit access to sensitive facilities",
            "Explaination": "It is essential for cybersecurity professionals to put controls in place that limit access to sensitive facilities, including data centers, server rooms, media storage facilities, evidence storage rooms, wiring closets, and cable distribution runs."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 3: Access Controls Concepts",
            "Question": "What is the purpose of <b>account reviews and audits</b>?",
            "Choices": [
                "To ensure users are using strong passwords",
                "To improve system performance",
                "To inspect permissions and ensure that segregation of duties is properly enforced",
                "To identify inactive user accounts"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "To inspect permissions and ensure that segregation of duties is properly enforced",
            "Explaination": "Account reviews and audits should inspect permissions to ensure that segregation of duties is properly enforced."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 3: Access Controls Concepts",
            "Question": "In which access control system do administrators assign users to roles based upon their job responsibilities and assign the permissions necessary to carry out different jobs to those roles?",
            "Choices": [
                "Discretionary access control (DAC) systems",
                "Mandatory access control (MAC) systems",
                "Role-based access control (RBAC) systems",
                "Attribute based access control (ABAC) systems"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Role-based access control (RBAC) systems",
            "Explaination": "In role-based access control (RBAC) systems, administrators assign users to roles based upon their job responsibilities and assign the permissions necessary to carry out different jobs to those roles."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 4: Network Security",
            "Question": "A network administrator needs to implement a solution that can identify and block malicious traffic in real-time by comparing network traffic against a database of known attack signatures. Which of the following would BEST meet this requirement?",
            "Choices": [
                "Network Intrusion Prevention System (NIPS)",
                "Host-based Intrusion Detection System (HIDS)",
                "Router",
                "Wi-Fi Access Point"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Network Intrusion Prevention System (NIPS)",
            "Explaination": "NIPS is more effective in preventing intrusions into a network. It actively blocks detected threats, whereas a HIDS monitors a specific host. A router directs network traffic, and a Wi-Fi access point provides wireless connectivity but neither actively prevent intrusions."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 4: Network Security",
            "Question": "An organization wants to ensure that its systems are configured securely from the start. What secure design principle does this BEST describe?",
            "Choices": [
                "Fail Securely",
                "Keep It Simple",
                "Zero Trust",
                "Secure Defaults"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Secure Defaults",
            "Explaination": "Secure Defaults ensure systems are configured to be secure from the start and that adjustments for usability are based on risk analysis."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 4: Network Security",
            "Question": "A company is setting up a web server that needs to be accessible from the internet. To protect its internal network, where should the web server be placed?",
            "Choices": [
                "VPN",
                "Internal Network",
                "Intranet",
                "DMZ"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "DMZ",
            "Explaination": "A DMZ (demilitarized zone) is a subnetwork that exposes an organization's external-facing services to an untrusted network, usually the internet."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 4: Network Security",
            "Question": "Which of the following is the MOST effective method to reduce the network attack surface of a system?",
            "Choices": [
                "Disabling unnecessary ports and services",
                "Ensuring that there are no group accounts on the system",
                "Uninstalling default software on the system",
                "Removing unnecessary system user accounts"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Disabling unnecessary ports and services",
            "Explaination": "Disabling unnecessary ports and services reduces the number of potential entry points for attackers, thereby reducing the attack surface."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 4: Network Security",
            "Question": "An organization wants to implement a network architecture where no user or device is implicitly trusted, and every access request is verified before granting access. Which security model aligns with this goal?",
            "Choices": [
                "Defense in Depth",
                "Privacy by Design",
                "Shared Responsibility",
                "Zero Trust"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Zero Trust",
            "Explaination": "Zero Trust architecture eliminates implicit trust and verifies every access request."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 4: Network Security",
            "Question": "A company decides to use a third-party to manage its cloud services, IT infrastructure, and end-user systems. Which of the following BEST describes this arrangement?",
            "Choices": [
                "Service-Level Agreement (SLA)",
                "Managed Service Provider (MSP)",
                "Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS)",
                "Platform as a Service (PaaS)"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Managed Service Provider (MSP)",
            "Explaination": "An MSP is a third-party company managing cloud services, IT infrastructure, or end-user systems on behalf of a customer, providing proactive monitoring, maintenance, and security management."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 4: Network Security",
            "Question": "Which of the following network security components operates at OSI Level 7?",
            "Choices": [
                "IGMP",
                "IP",
                "SNMP",
                "ICMP"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "SNMP",
            "Explaination": "Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP) is an application-level protocol (level 7), used to configure and monitor devices attached to networks. Internet Protocol (IP), Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP) and Internet Group Management Protocol (IGMP) are level 3 protocols."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 4: Network Security",
            "Question": "A company discovers its web server is the target of many requests, rendering it inaccessible to legitimate users. Which type of attack is it experiencing?",
            "Choices": [
                "Denials of Service",
                "Phishing",
                "Cross-site Scripting",
                "Side Channel Attack"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Denials of Service",
            "Explaination": "A denial-of-service attack (DoS) compromises the availability of a system or service through a malicious overload of requests."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 4: Network Security",
            "Question": "What is the purpose of a Memorandum of Understanding (MOU)?",
            "Choices": [
                "A legally binding contract outlining specific services and penalties",
                "A non-binding document outlining the intent to cooperate or collaborate",
                "A detailed technical specification for system integration",
                "A risk assessment report for cloud services"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "A non-binding document outlining the intent to cooperate or collaborate",
            "Explaination": "A MOU is a non-binding document outlining the intent to cooperate or collaborate and acts as a preliminary agreement for a future formal contract."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 4: Network Security",
            "Question": "Which of the following IPv6 address types is used for one-to-many communication?",
            "Choices": [
                "Unicast",
                "Anycast",
                "Multicast",
                "Broadcast"
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Multicast",
            "Explaination": "IPv6 supports three types of addresses, these are: Unicast (one-to-one), Anycast (one-to-nearest) and Multicast (one-to-many). Broadcast is not supported in IPv6."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 5: Security Operations",
            "Question": "During a security incident, a technician needs to securely erase data on a decommissioned hard drive that may be reused later. Which method is MOST appropriate?",
            "Choices": [
                "Formatting the drive.",
                "Overwriting the data.",
                "Degaussing the drive.",
                "Physically destroying the drive."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Overwriting the data.",
            "Explaination": "Overwriting the data is the most secure method to ensure that sensitive data on the server�s hard drives is completely destroyed if you would like to potentially reuse the drives."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 5: Security Operations",
            "Question": "An organization wants to ensure that its sensitive data is marked appropriately to maintain consistent handling. Which of the following practices should be implemented?",
            "Choices": [
                "Data Encryption.",
                "Data Retention.",
                "Data Labeling.",
                "Data Destruction."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Data Labeling.",
            "Explaination": "When an organization classifies information, it should establish labeling requirements to apply consistent markings to sensitive data, helping users consistently identify sensitive information and handle it appropriately."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 5: Security Operations",
            "Question": "A security analyst is tasked with connecting events from different systems to identify potential security threats. Which attribute of effective logging is MOST useful for this task?",
            "Choices": [
                "Accountability.",
                "Auditability.",
                "Availability.",
                "Traceability."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Traceability.",
            "Explaination": "Traceability is the attribute of effective logging that is most useful for connecting the dots between different events and identifying any potential security threats."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 5: Security Operations",
            "Question": "An organization wants to improve its ability to identify the cause of security incidents. Which of the following should be implemented?",
            "Choices": [
                "NIDS.",
                "DBMS.",
                "IAM.",
                "SIEM."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "SIEM.",
            "Explaination": "A SIEM (Security Information and Event Management) solution would best aid in centralizing, protecting, and analyzing log entries."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 5: Security Operations",
            "Question": "After a security breach, an organization decides to implement a new policy requiring employees to use strong, unique passwords. Which type of policy is this?",
            "Choices": [
                "Acceptable Use Policy (AUP).",
                "Bring Your Own Device (BYOD) Policy.",
                "Data Handling Policy.",
                "Password Policy."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Password Policy.",
            "Explaination": "Implementing a policy requiring strong, unique passwords directly aligns with a password policy."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 5: Security Operations",
            "Question": "What is the PRIMARY goal of security awareness training?",
            "Choices": [
                "To ensure compliance with legal requirements.",
                "To equip people to recognize and respond to threats.",
                "To reduce the workload of the IT department.",
                "To test employees' knowledge of security policies."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "To equip people to recognize and respond to threats.",
            "Explaination": "Security awareness training is a crucial part of any cybersecurity strategy and equips people to recognize and respond to threats."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 5: Security Operations",
            "Question": "An organization wants to allow employees to use their personal devices for work while maintaining security. Which policy should be implemented?",
            "Choices": [
                "Acceptable Use Policy (AUP).",
                "Change Management Policy.",
                "Data Handling Policy.",
                "Bring Your Own Device (BYOD) Policy."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Bring Your Own Device (BYOD) Policy.",
            "Explaination": "A BYOD policy provides appropriate guidelines for employees using personal smartphones for work-related tasks."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 5: Security Operations",
            "Question": "An organization needs to ensure that it can prove a customer agreed to certain terms. Which cryptographic goal is MOST relevant?",
            "Choices": [
                "Confidentiality.",
                "Integrity.",
                "Authentication.",
                "Non-repudiation."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Non-repudiation.",
            "Explaination": "Applying a digital signature to a contract so that the recipient can prove that she agreed to its terms. The goal of cryptography that most directly describes this action is Non-repudiation."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 5: Security Operations",
            "Question": "Which security control objective is achieved by classifying data based on its sensitivity?",
            "Choices": [
                "Data Integrity.",
                "Data Confidentiality.",
                "Data Availability.",
                "Data Authentication."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Data Confidentiality.",
            "Explaination": "Classification identifies the degree of harm to the organization if an information asset is divulged to an unauthorized person and is focused on maintaining the confidentiality of the data based on the data sensitivity."
        },
        {
            "DomainOfKnowledge": "ISC2 CC Domain 5: Security Operations",
            "Question": "What is the purpose of baselining in configuration management?",
            "Choices": [
                "Patch management.",
                "Version control.",
                "System hardening.",
                "Providing a point of comparison for future system changes."
            ],
            "AnswerKey": "Providing a point of comparison for future system changes.",
            "Explaination": "Creating a baseline for each system at a specific point in time allows for a comparison of system changes in the future."
        }
    ]
}